Guide to the Roman Gulʹ Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1881-1966; Series V; 0.5; (3 boxes)
  - PEOPLE
    - Groups
      - Gul', Roman Borisovich and
        - Fedin, Konstantin, and Krymov, Vl. (Vladimir), 1927 (Box 83, Folder 1991)
        - Pil'niak, Boris Andreevich, 1927 (Box 83, Folder 1992)
        - Fedin, Konstantin, 1928 (Box 83, Folder 1993)
        - Gruzdev, Il'ia Aleksandrovich; Fedin, Konstantin; Guzdeva, M., 1928 (Box 83, Folder 1994)
        - Krymova, B. V.; Fedin, Konstantin Aleksandrovich, 1928 (Box 83, Folder 1995)
        - Nikitin, Nikolai, 1928 (Box 83, Folder 1996)
        - Fedin, Konstantin, 1930 (Box 83, Folder 1997)
        - Burtsev, Vladimir L'vovich, 1931 (Box 83, Folder 1998)
        - Nicolaevsky, Boris; Krymova, B. V., 1931 (Box 83, Folder 1999)
        - Tolstoi, Aleksei Nikolaevich; Krymova, B. V., 1931 (Box 83, Folder 2000)
        - Feder, Jack, and unidentified persons, 1936 (Box 83, Folder 2001)
        - Filippov, Elagin, unidentified, Kovalenko, Bushman, unidentified, Rybinskii, Kasim, Anstei, Menchukov, Tverskoi, Nartsissov, 1949 (Box 83, Folder 2002)
        - Rechitskii, Buka, Zarudnyi, Zotov, and others, [1949?] (Box 83, Folder 2003)
        - Gul', Ol'ga Andreevna; IUreva, Zoia; Vitlin, [1960?] (Box 83, Folder 2004)
        - Gul', Ol'ga Andreevna; Novikov, V. N., [1960] (Box 83, Folder 2005)
        - Varshavskii, V. S., 1966 (Box 83, Folder 2006)
        - Efremov, Nik. Evdok [?]; Faier, M., n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2007)
      - IAkovlev, B. A.; Antonov; Polamarchuk, Legestaev, [1949?] (Box 83, Folder 2008)
      - IAshchenko, Aleksandr Semenovich
        - with his wife, 1926 (Box 83, Folder 2009)
        - with his wife, Shkliaver, S.; Diushek, B., and an unidentified lady, 1923 (Box 83, Folder 2010)
      - Ivanov, Georgii Vladimirovich, and
        - Odoevtseva, Irina Vladimirovna, 1958 (Box 83, Folder 2011)
        - Odoevtseva, Irina Vladimirovna and unidentified persons, 1958 (Box 83, Folder 2012)
      - Korvin-Piotrovskii, Vladimir L'vovich; Rafal'skii, Sergei Milich, 1959 (Box 83, Folder 2013)
      - Krymov, Vladimir Pimenovich and his wife Berta Vladimirovna, 1963 (Box 83, Folder 2014)
      - Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich; Christensen, [P. P.?]; Boris Reinstein "conferring on the famine relief", 1921 (Box 83, Folder 2015)
      - Members of "Liga" and "RND" picketing the Soviet consulate in New York, 1950 (Box 83, Folder 2016)
      - Murav'ev Mikhail Artem'evich with a group of officers, not after 1918 (Box 83, Folder 2017)
      - Odorchenko, IUrii with his wife, 1950, 1959 (Box 83, Folder 2018)
      - Ofrosimov, IUrii Viktorovich with his wife, 1947 (Box 83, Folder 2019)
      - Paustovskii, Konstantin; Zaitsev, Boris Konstantinovich, 1963 (Box 83, Folder 2020)
      - Raevskii, Georgii, and
        - his wife and daughter, 1961 (Box 83, Folder 2021)
        - Odarchenko, IUrii Pavlovich, 1949 (Box 83, Folder 2022)
      - Slater, Lidiia, and
        - a group of P.E.N. members: Argus, Vitlin, Landsbergis, IUr'eva, Gul', Rannit, Alekseeva, and others, 1963 (Box 83, Folder 2023)
        - IUr'eva, Vitlin, Gul', Khostovskii[?], [1963] (Box 83, Folder 2024)
      - Turoverov, Nikolai, and
        - his brother Aleksandr, 1961 (Box 83, Folder 2025)
        - Turoverova, Natasha; Turoverov, Aleksandr and Ivan, 1961 (Box 83, Folder 2026)
      - Vitlin, Iosif with his wife, [1960] (Box 83, Folder 2027)
    - Portraits
      - Lebedev, S., [192-?] (Box 84, Folder 2028)
      - Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich, 1921, [1924] (Box 84, Folder 2029)
      - Ofrosimov, IUrii Viktorovich, 1959 (Box 84, Folder 2030)
      - Pasternak, Boris, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2031)
      - Volshii, Maks, [1918?] (Box 84, Folder 2032)
  - PLACES AND OTHERS
    - Places and others, [1918?-64?], n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2033-45)
  - ALBUM
    - "Hard-labour Camp in Siberia", n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2046)
- Personal Papers, 1919-65; Series VI; 0.5; (1 box)
  Series VI, Personal Papers, is found in Box 85. The material is arranged by subject and then alphabetically or choronologically.
  - Autograph-inscriptions, 1921-65, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2047)
  - Documents and papers, 1933-61, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2048)
  - Gul', R. B.: "Moia kratkaia biografiia" and a page from J.B.D., 1935, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2049)
  - Financial papers, 1935-64, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2050)
  - Invitations, 1936-65, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2051)
  - Letters, [1919?]-38, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2052)
  - Masonic documents
    - Correspondence, 1936-54 (Box 85, Folder 2053-55)
    - Grande Loge de France: Diplôme de maître and membership card, 1937, 1945 (Box 85, Folder 2056)
    - Invitations, 1945 (Box 85, Folder 2057)
    - Miscellany, 1946, [1950?], n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2058-61)
  - New York Public Library: call slips, var. dates (Box 85, Folder 2062)
  - Reviews, [1936]-49, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2063-67)
  - Writings, [1950-62], n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2068)
- Special Files, 1931-64; Series VII; 0.5; (1 box)
  Series VII, Special Files, fills Boxes 86-87. The material is arranged by subject and then alphabetically.
  - American Committee, 1951-64, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 2069)
  - "The Cases", 1919-51, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 2070-75)
  - Curricula vitae, 1913-[62], n.d. (Box 86, Folder 2076-2101)
  - International P. E. N. Club, 1957, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 2102)
  - Letters, [1948?]-53, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 2103)
  - Political miscellany, 1931-64, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 2104-06)
  - Miscellany, var. dates (Box 87, Folder 2107-21)
- Oversize, 1927-53; 2.01; (1 box)
  - Buldakova, Anna Grigor'evna, 1927-29, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 2122)
  - Za svobodu: organ Rossiiskogo narodnogo dvizheniià Nos. 2-4, 10, 13-14, 1952-53 (Box 88, Folder 2123)